Fitssum W. Haile

(202) 469 0640 Silver Spring, MD fitsum.wolde@gmail.com https://fitssum.github.io/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/fitssum-haile/

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer with diverse experience in research and financial analysis. Skilled in distilling facts, trends and patterns from large amounts of data to simplified solutions. Create interactive products with tailored messages strongly influenced by technology and communication skills.

SKILLS

- Web Development: HTML, CSS, SASS, Javascript, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, PHP, Jasmine, RSpec, Git, Github, Agile/scrum, Bootstrap, wire framing, user stories/requirements planning, and test driven development.
- Analysis: IBM Analyst's Notebook.
- Web Management Systems: Joomla, Drupal 7, Wordpress
- Graphic Designing: Adobe Indesign, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop.

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer, General Assembly Washington D.C, USA

May 2017 to present

 Developed portfolio and projects with the latest front- and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies. These include Angular 4 app with MEAN stack at the back-end, a bikeshare application allowing users to see the availability of bikes and checkout built with Ruby and Ruby on Rails, a sports app using Angular JS at the front end and api calls using Rails on the back-end, a Trivia game implemented with Javascript and DOM manipulation, among others. (See my GA portfolio)

Information Analyst, United Nations Mission in the Republic of South Sudan (UNMISS), Joint Mission Analysis Centre (JMAC), Juba, South Sudan

June 2012 to June 2016

- Analyzed classified financial documents into analytical products. These include research papers, personal profiling using IBM Analyst Notebook, warning notes, relationship-mapping and code cables within JMAC Thematic Team that supported mission leadership in decision-making.
- Drafted Early Warning and Early Response weekly product as part of the EW team.

Communication Officer, African Union (AU)

Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

March 2010 to May 2012

- Developed AMESD public, project and forum websites with Joomla and Drupal CMS and Javascript.
- Established and moderated interactive virtual discussion forum in AMESD public website that
 engaged African environmental policy-makers into discussions on environmental and developmental
 issues. Established documents database/filing system with Drupal CMS that helped keep records of
 program achievements.
- Drafted and implemented AMESD continental communication strategy for a €21mil project implemented in 48 countries.
- Designed communication products using Adobe Creative Suite for project partners.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

- Media Project Coordinator, Lambadina Institute Health and Development Communication
- Special Assistant to Sector General, United Nations Mission in Liberia (UNMIL)
- Journalist, The Reporter English weekly newspaper

EDUCATION

- General Assembly, Web Development Immersive, 2017
- B. A. Degree in Foreign Language and Literature, Addis Ababa University, 2004 (English Literature, Journalism, Communication majors)
- High School Diploma, Nativity Catholic Cathedral School, Addis Ababa, 1998

CERTIFICATES OF TRAINING

- Front-end Web Development, University of California, Davis, 2016 2016
- Conflict Management, Analysis and Resolution, Juba, South Sudan, 06 July 2015
- United Nations Joint Mission Analysis Centres Course, Oslo, Norway, 23 Nov. 2014